You may want to take a closer look.
قد ترغبون في إلقاء نظرة فاحصة.
There's more to this painting than meets the eye.
هذه أكثرمن لوحة يكمن أن تراها العين.
And yes, it's an acrylic painting of a man,
فعلا إنه رسم إكريليكي لرجل ،
but I didn't paint it on canvas.
ولكن لم أرسمه على قماش.
I painted it directly on top of the man.
رسمته مباشرة على جسد الرجل.
What I do in my art is I skip the canvas altogether,
ما أفعله في فني أنه أتخطى القماش كليا
and if I want to paint your portrait,
فإذا كنت أريد أن أرسم لك صورتك،
I'm painting it on you, physically on you.
سأرسم على جسدك مباشرة
That also means you're probably going to end up
وهذا يعني أيضا أنه ربما تسير لنهايتك
with an earful of paint,
مع توبيخ قاس في الرسم
because I need to paint your ear on your ear.
لأنني بحاجة لرسم أذنك على إذنك.
Everything in this scene, the person, the clothes,
كل شيء في هذا المشهد، الشخص، الملابس،
chairs, wall, gets covered in a mask of paint
الكراسي، الجدار، تغطى بقناع من الطلاء
that mimics what's directly below it,
يحاكي ما تحته مباشرة،
and in this way, I'm able to take a three-dimensional scene
وبهذه الطريقة ، أكون قادرة على التقاط مشهد ثلاثي الأبعاد
and make it look like a two-dimensional painting.
وجعله يبدو وكأنه لوحة ثنائية الأبعاد.
I can photograph it from any angle,
ويمكن لي التقاط صور له من أي زاوية،
and it will still look 2D.
و ستظل تبدو ثنائية الأبعاد.
There's no Photoshop here.
لا يوجد أي فوتوشوب هنا.
This is just a photo
إنها مجرد صورة
of one of my three-dimensional paintings.
واحدة من لوحاتي ثلاثية الأبعاد.
You might be wondering how I came up with this idea
ربما تتساءلون كيف أتيت بهذه الفكرة
of turning people into paintings.
لتحويل الأشخاص إلى لوحات.
But originally, this had nothing to do
لكن هذا في الأصل، لم تكن له علاقة
with either people or paint.
بالأشخاص أو الرسم.
It was about shadows.
له علاقة بالظلال.
I was fascinated with the absence of light,
لقد فتنت بغياب الضوء،
and I wanted to find a way that I could give it materiality
وكنت أرغب في البحث عن طريقة تعطيه مادية
and pin it down before it changed.
وتحدده قبل أن يتغير.
I came up with the idea of painting shadows.
جئت بفكرة رسم الظلال.
I loved that I could hide within this shadow
أحببت أنه يمكنني إخفاء الظل داخل
my own painted version,
نوعية رسمي الخاصة ،
and it would be almost invisible
وسيكون غير مرئي تقريبا
until the light changed, and all of a sudden
حتى مع تغير الضوء، وفجأة
my shadow would be brought to the light.
سيتنقل الظل إلى ضوء.
I wanted to think about what else I could put shadows on,
كنت أفكر في من يمكنني أن أضع الظلال عليه،
and I thought of my friend Bernie.
وفكرت في صديقي بيرني.
But I didn't just want to paint the shadows.
لم أكن أريد فقط أن أرسم الظلال.
I also wanted to paint the highlights
أردت أيضا أن رسم أقوى من ذلك
and create a mapping on his body in greyscale.
وإنشاءرسم تفصيلي على جسمه باللون الرمادي.
I had a very specific vision of what this would look like,
كان لي رؤية محددة جداً على ما سيبدوعليه،
and as I was painting him,
و عندما كنت أرسمه،
I made sure to follow that very closely.
حرصت على أن أتابع ذلك عن كثب.
But something kept on flickering before my eyes.
ولكن شيء ما أبقى على التردد أمام عيني.
I wasn't quite sure what I was looking at.
لم أكن متأكدة تماما مما سيبدو عليه .
And then when I took that moment to take a step back,
وعندما أخدت لحظة وعدت خطوة إلى الوراء،
magic.
إنه سحر.
I had turned my friend into a painting.
لقد حولت صديقي إلى لوحة.
I couldn't have foreseen that
لم أكن أتوقع ذلك
when I wanted to paint a shadow,
عندما أردت أن أرسم الظل،
I would pull out this whole other dimension,
كنت أود أن أسحب هذا البعد الآخر كله،
that I would collapse it,
التي رغبت في طيه ,
that I would take a painting and make it my friend
و آخد لوحة وأحولها لصديقي
and then bring him back to a painting.
ومن ثم إعادتها مرة أخرى إلى لوحة.
I was a little conflicted though,
كنت قليلا متناقضة على الرغم من
because I was so excited about what I'd found,
أنني كنت سعيدة للغاية بما وجدت،
but I was just about to graduate from college
لكنني كنت على وشك التخرج من الكلية
with a degree in political science,
بإمتياز في العلوم السياسية،
and I'd always had this dream
وقد كان لي دائماً هذا الحلم
of going to Washington, D.C.,
بالذهاب إلى العاصمة واشنطن،
and sitting at a desk
والجلوس في مكتب
and working in government.
والعمل في الحكومة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Why did this have to get in the way of all that?
لماذا حصل كل هذا بهذه الطريقة ؟
I made the tough decision
إتخدت قراراً صعباً
of going home after graduation
بالعودة إلى المنزل بعد التخرج
and not going up to Capitol Hill,
وعدم الذهاب إلى مبنى الكابيتول هيل،
but going down to my parents' basement
لكن الذهاب للطابق السفلي
and making it my job to learn how to paint.
و أجعل من عملي هو تعلم كيف أرسم.
I had no idea where to begin.
لم تكن لدي أي فكرة من أين أبدأ.
The last time I'd painted,
آخر مرة كنت قد رسمت فيها ،
I was 16 years old at summer camp,
كان عمري 16 عاماً في مخيم صيفي،
and I didn't want to teach myself how to paint
ولم أرغب في تعليم نفسي كيفية الرسم
by copying the old masters
عن طريق نسخ أعمال الفنانين القدامى
or stretching a canvas
أو بذل جهد في لوحة
and practicing over and over again on that surface,
وأمارس ذلك مرارا وتكرارا ،
because that's not what this project was about for me.
لأن ذلك ليس ماهية المشروع بالنسبة لي.
It was about space and light.
كان ذلك عن الفضاء والضوء.
My early canvases ended up being
كانت لوحاتي الأولى عبارة عن
things that you wouldn't expect to be used as canvas,
أفكار لن تتوقعوا أن تستعمل كلوحات،
like fried food.
مثل الطعام المقلي.
It's nearly impossible
إنه من المستحيل تقريبا
to get paint to stick to the grease in an egg.
طلاء الدهون الموجودة في البيضة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Even harder was getting paint to stick
و الأصعب من ذلك طلاء
to the acid in a grapefruit.
الحمض الموجود في االليمون .
It just would erase my brush strokes
كنت أريد مجرد محوها بالفرشاة
like invisible ink.
مثل الحبر الخفي.
I'd put something down, and instantly it would be gone.
أجعل شيء ما أسفله ، وعلى الفور سيختفي.
And if I wanted to paint on people,
لكن إذا أردت أن أرسم على الأشخاص،
well, I was a little bit embarrassed
حسنا، كنت قليلا محرجة
to bring people down into my studio
لأحضر الناس في الاستوديو الخاص بي
and show them that I spent my days in a basement
وأبين لهم أني قضيت أيامي في الطابق السفلي
putting paint on toast.
أضع الطلاء على نخب.
It just seemed like it made more sense
يبدو تماما مثل أنه سيكون من المنطقي أكثر
to practice by painting on myself.
أن أقوم بطلاء نفسي.
One of my favorite models actually ended up being
واحد من نماذجي المفضلة التي انتهيت منها كانت
a retired old man
رجل متقاعد كبير السن
who not only didn't mind sitting still
لم يمانع فقط بأن يبقى جالسا
and getting the paint in his ears,
ويتم طلاء أذنيه ،
but he also didn't really have much embarrassment
بل أيضا لم يكن لديه الكثير من الإحراج
about being taken out into very public places
أن يكون ذلك في الأماكن العامة
for exhibition,
للعرض ،
like the Metro.
مثل المترو.
I was having so much fun with this process.
حظيت بالكتير من المتعة أثناء هذه العملية.
I was teaching myself how to paint in all these different styles,
لقد كنت أدرس نفسي كيف أرسم على كل هذه الأنماط المختلفة،
and I wanted to see what else I could do with it.
وأردت أن أرى ماذا يمكن أن أفعل حيال ذلك.
I came together with a collaborator, Sheila Vand,
كنت مع مساعدة لي إسمها شيلا فاند،
and we had the idea of creating paintings
لدينا فكرة إنشاء لوحات
in a more unusual surface,
على مساحة أكثر غرابة،
and that was milk.
وقد كانت هذه المساحة هي الحليب.
We got a pool. We filled it with milk.
حصلنا على بركة. وملأناها بالحليب.
We filled it with Sheila. And I began painting.
ووضعنا فيها شايلا. وبدأت الرسم .
And the images were always
وكانت الصور دائماً
completely unexpected in the end,
غير متوقعة تماما في نهاية المطاف،
because I could have a very specific image
لأنه كانت لدي صورة محددة للغاية
about how it would turn out,
كيف ستتحول ،
I could paint it to match that,
ويمكن لي أن أرسمها لتطابق ذلك،
but the moment that Sheila laid back into the milk,
ولكن في اللحظة التي عادت فيها شايلا إلى بركة الحليب،
everything would change.
سيتغير كل شيء.
It was in constant flux,
كان ذلك في تغير مستمر،
and we had to, rather than fight it, embrace it,
وكان علينا، بدلاً من محاربة ذلك أن نبني عليه ،
see where the milk would take us
ونرى أين سيأخدنا الحليب
and compensate to make it even better.
وتعويض ذلك لجعله أفضل.
Sometimes, when Sheila would lay down in the milk,
في بعض الأحيان، عندما كانت شايلا تستلقي في الحليب،
it would wash all the paint off of her arms,
كان يغسل الطلاء ذراعيها،
and it might seem a little bit clumsy,
وقد يبدو لكم ذلك أخرق قليلا،
but our solution would be, okay, hide your arms.
لكن الحل الذي إقترحناه ، كان إخفاء ذراعيها .
And one time, she got so much milk in her hair
وفي مرة إمتلأ شعرها بالحليب
that it just smeared all the paint off of her face.
وغطى كل ملامح وجهها.
All right, well, hide your face.
حسنا،أخف وجهك.
And we ended up with something far more elegant
وانتهى بنا المطاف مع شيء أكثر أناقة
than we could have imagined,
مما يمكن أن نتصور،
even though this is essentially the same solution
على الرغم من أن هذا هو أساسا نفس الحل
that a frustrated kid uses when he can't draw hands,
الذي يستخدمه طفل محبط عندما لا يمكنه رسم اليدين،
just hiding them in the pockets.
وذلك فقط بإخفائها في الجيوب.
When we started out on the milk project,
عندما بدأنا في مشروع الحليب هذا
and when I started out,
وعندما بدأت،
I couldn't have foreseen that I would go
لم أستطع أن أتنبأ أنني سأمضي
from pursuing my dream in politics
في السعي إلى تحقيق حلمي في الحياة السياسية
and working at a desk
والعمل في مكتب
to tripping over a shadow
لتتخلص من ظل
and then turning people into paintings
وبعد ذلك تحول الناس إلى اللوحات
and painting on people in a pool of milk.
والرسم على الأشخاص في بركة حليب.
But then again, I guess it's also not unforeseeable
ولكن مرة أخرى، أنا أعتقد أيضا أنه ليست من غير المتوقع
that you can find the strange in the familiar,
أن تجد الغرابة في المألوف،
as long as you're willing to look beyond
طالما كنت على استعداد للنظر فيما وراء
what's already been brought to light,
ما هوأصلا موجود تحت الضوء،
that you can see what's below the surface,
عندها يمكنك أن ترى ما تحت السطح،
hiding in the shadows,
والمخبأ في الظلال،
and recognize that there can be more there
وتعترف بأنه يمكن أن يكون هناك أكثر
than meets the eye.
مما تراه العين.
Thank you.
شكرا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)